Gibrail Lashekham

CONTACT 2379 Dundas Street West INFORMATION

Toronto, ON M6P 1X2

Phone: 647-785-8510

E-mail: gibrail.lash@hotmail.com WWW: www.gibrail-lash.github.io

CAREER PROFILE

Mechanical EIT with 3 years experience from mechanical design, to manufacturing, to project management. Developed pivotal operations to assist start-up in reaching profitability. Advanced skill in numerous CAD/CAE tools with 8+ years of personal, educational, and professional work

Core competencies include Systems Design, Computational Fluid Dynamics and Rapid Prototyping. Educational credentials include a Masters Degree from University of Toronto, and a Solid-Works Professional Certification (CSWP)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Linear Computing Inc.

Mississauga, ON

Jr. Mechanical Engineer

Aug 2017 – Aug 2020

- Heavily involved in the design, prototyping, and manufacturing of mechanical systems, custom test fixtures, and components utilizing 3D CAD software and manufacturing tools
- Oversee manufacturing department of 4 employees, ensuring completion of project deliverables, and responsible for complete training of machinery/operations/procedures
- Responsible for the creation of manufacturing processes and the drafting of SOPs
- Adept problem solver, developed and implemented numerous processes and manufacturing modifications increasing productivity by 50%

Hartford Steam Boiler Inspection & Insurance

Toronto, ON

Administrative Assistant

Jun 2015 – Jan 2016

- Provided administrative support to team with demonstrated ability to balance multiple tasks while meeting demanding deadlines
- Utilized strong analytical & organizational skills to complete tasks with minimal supervision

EDUCATION

University of Toronto

Toronto, ON

Master of Engineering – Mechanical Engineering

Jan 2018 - Jun 2019

Specialization: Sustainable Energy Systems

• Excelled in Rapid Prototyping and Systems Design

Ryerson University

Toronto, ON

Bachelor of Engineering – Mechanical Engineering

Sep 2012 - Jun 2016

Specialization: Design of Mechanical Systems

KEY SKILLS

Software: SolidWorks, CATIA V5, ANSYS Fluent, Fusion 360, Altium Designer, MS Excel

Programming: MATLAB, Python, Web Design (HTML, CSS, JS) Technical: Arduino, GD&T, 3D Print, Technical Documentation

Relevant Courses: Systems Engineering, Statistics, Reliability & Failure Analysis

INTERESTS

Astronomy, Stephen King Novels, Boxing, Trekking & Outdoor Activities, Tennis